#### Mahendra Duwal Shrestha

4831 E Summit Cir Apt 136 ● Knoxville, TN 37919 ● (865) 441-7363 ● mduwalsh@vols.utk.edu

• <u>duwal.mahendra@gmail.com</u>

### **SUMMARY**

5 years of programming experience. A software engineer with 2.5 years of professional industry experience in C#, Asp.Net MVC, Java, Grails. Proven abilities in analysis, unit testing and application development in both new and existing projects. 2.5 years of research experience in developing mathematical simulation programs involving cluster computations in C/C++.

## **EDUCATION**

MS in Computer Science, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville, GPA: 3.88

2014-2017

*Major courses taken*: Computer Systems Organization, Software Systems, Algorithms (and Data Structures), Introduction to Pattern Recognition, Databases and Scripting Languages, Applied Cryptography, Distributed System Algorithms

Thesis: Efficient Simulation Of A Simple Evolutionary System

BE in Electronics and Communication Engineering, Pulchowk Engineering

2007-2011

Campus, Tribhuvan University, Nepal, GPA: 3.8

### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

• Programming Language: C, C++, C#, Java, Groovy, Javascript, Python

Technologies: ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC, Groovy on Grails, Nodejs, HTML, JSON,

Web services, WCF services, REST, SOAP, Hibernate, Entity Framework,

Spring MVC, Ajax, Jquery, JUnit, NUnit

Version Control: git, subversionDatabases: MYSQL, MSSQL

Tools: Gnuplot, pthreads, CUDA, OpenMP, Hadoop, Visual Studio, TFS, Eclipse,

IntellijIdea, Net beans, Resharper, TortoiseSVN, Emacs, Latex

SDLC: Agile Scrum, WaterfallPlatforms: Linux, Windows, Unix

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Graduate Teaching / Research Assistant**, The University of Tennessee, TN

8/2014 – 2017

- Graded assignments and projects, and tutored for undergraduate classes 'Algorithm Analysis and Automata' and 'Software Engineering' during academic year 2014 - 2015
- Developed programs for simulations of computational models and plotting graphs using C/C++ and **gnuplot** for Dr. Sergey Gavrilets in Ecology and Evolutionary Biology Department during 2014 2017
- Used cluster computing for simulations and fixed maintenance issues in the Linux cluster

### Software Engineer, Deerwalk Services Pvt. Ltd., Nepal

1/2012 - 7/2014

- Developed web applications using **agile** methodology for health care system management in US using **ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC** and **C#** as a member of outsourcing service provider team
- Designed and developed database schema and stored procedures in MSSQL
- Developed and maintained US health care system management web application modules using **Grails** framework as a member of Deerwalk's product's team
- Designed and developed database schema, scripts and stored procedures in MYSQL
- Led developer's team for development and optimization of generic MYSQL scripts for importing staged data from multiple clients into company's product's database system